everybody and welcome to today's
assembly before we talk about today's
assembly let's practice
the sign of the week which is road
safety and with road safety
that the hands start
level with the shoulders and then they
come down
in a parallel movement and then we draw
both hands
back into the body if we do that again
hands start
next to shoulders they come down in a
parallel motion
and then we draw the hands back that's
road safety
right so the assembly today is all about
keeping safe
on and near roads
so what are you going to learn about in
today's assembly we're going to learn
about what actually road safety is
um some facts about road safety i'm
going to give you some safety tips for
pedestrians
i'm going to give you some safety tips
for cyclists and also some safety tips
for vehicle users namely passengers
so what does road safety actually mean
well road safety refers to the methods
and the measures used to prevent road
users being killed
or injured road users
include pedestrians cyclists motorists
and passengers
so before we actually talk about some
safety tips for road users
let's look at some facts actually about
road safety
well as it says up there there are over
1 million road traffic deaths
every year worldwide on average
there are five people killed on the road
every day just in the uk
on average the 65 people are seriously
injured
on the road every day in the uk and road
traffic accidents are the number one
cause of death
amongst young people between 15 and 29
years of age
when wearing a seat belt this can reduce
the risk of a fatal injury by 50
if you were sitting in the front and 75
if you were sitting at the back
or you say if you were a rear seat
passenger
so firstly let's have a look at some
safety tips for pedestrians so when
crossing the road you need to stop
you need to look you need to listen and
you need to think
so stop this means stop when you reach a
road that you want to cross
look means look right look left and then
right again
listen means listen before you cross for
any vehicles approaching
and think means think about when and
where it is safe
to cross the road
here are some more safety tips for
pedestrians always use the pedestrian
crossings when possible
always walk on pavements and footpaths
never cross the road on a bend and watch
for any turning cars never cross
between between behind or in front of
parked vehicles
and very importantly don't get
distracted when crossing the road and
don't use mobile devices like mobile
phones
be bright at night and wear a reflective
gear
and if you're crossing into zebra or
pedestrian crossing wait for the traffic
to stop
sometimes when cars approach or vehicles
approach zebras
they don't automatically stop and
sometimes they'll go straight across so
you need to make sure
that the vehicles stop before you step
onto the zebra crossing
in order to cross the road
now let's look at some safety tips for
cyclists
well firstly always wear a cycle helmet
see the cycle helmet here make sure you
wear a cycle helmet it's in good
condition
do not wear headphones while cycling and
always ride on the road
or the cycle paths obey rules
and follow road signs use hand signals
if you turn in bright
or you turn in left make sure your bike
is in good condition
particularly the lights and the brakes
see
and be seen wear bright clothing and
have bike reflectors and lights
make sure you the your lights and your
bike reflectors are clean
and not covered in dirt concentrate and
pay attention to road hazards
and if possible try avoid cycling at
night because more accidents actually
occur
at night time when it's getting darker
if you need to carry something use a
backpack don't carry things up
holding on to the handlebars like say
put them in a backpack put that onto
your back it's much safer
well now let's look at some safety tips
for vehicle passengers
so that's whether you're in a car or
you're on a bus or on the school bus
first of all buckle up wear a seatbelt
and make sure it fits snugly if it's not
not too loose don't distract the driver
don't block the driver's view in the
mirror that's particularly if you're a
passenger in a car and you're sitting
in the back never lean or wave out of
the window
never throw objects out of the window
this not only could distract your driver
but obviously the danger
to other vehicles on the road as well
don't touch the door handles while the
car is moving
and take care when you're exiting the
school bus and never walk behind the bus
as you get off remember the bus stop
it's not a playground it's always be
sensible
when you're waiting for the bus when
you're waiting the bus wait for the bus
to stop
and the drive to give you the okay
before you actually get onto the school
bus
so this assembly links to the ultimate
personal quality's confidence
as we all need to show confidence when
crossing or using the road
either on a bike or as a passenger or if
or if we're a pedestrian walking near
the road
so we all need to show confidence
and finally let's just reinforce the
safety messages
around corona rice and how we can help
to defeat
defeat this horrible virus
so washing hands more often and for 20
seconds each time
cover your face if you if you can in
public spaces and always use a tissue
with sneezes
and then bin it and keep at least a
meter and ideally two meters from other
people
not in your household so in summary to
beat the virus
it's hands face and space
thank you